Melville Clark Papers
Melville Clark Papers
1906-1953
Clark, Melville
30 linear ft.
Papers of the American musician, inventor of the Clark Irish harp; Syracuse businessman, owner of Clark Music Co., founded by his father. Correspondence (1908-1950); calendars (1905-1953), heavily annotated; subject files; scrapbooks and photographs. Also, material relating to the Central New York Music Festival and the Syracuse Symphony Orchestra.
149728
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Melville Clark Papers are arranged in four series. Correspondence contains letters, cards and other written correspondence, arranged chronologically. Daily calendars contains nearly fifty years of Clark's daily calendar, arranged chronologically. Reference files are arranged alphabetically and include topics such as "Harp," "Pianos," "Organs." Miscellaneous includes a scrapbook of advertisements using musical instruments, insurance and other miscellaneous papers, and photographs.
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Music; Business and Industry; Clark, Melville.; Central New York Music Festival.; Clark Music Company (Syracuse, N.Y.); Syracuse Symphony Orchestra.; Businessmen -- New York (State) -- Syracuse.; Harp -- Instruction and study.; Harpists -- United States.; Music -- 20th century.; Music trade -- New York (State) -- Syracuse.; Musicians -- United States.; Calendars (documents); Correspondence.; Instructional materials.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Businessmen; Musicians.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Letters, 1908-1923
    - Aa-Be (Box 1)
    - Bi-Cz (Box 2)
    - Da-E (Box 3)
    - F-Gy (Box 4)
    - Ha-I (Box 5)
    - J-K (Box 6)
    - La-My (Box 7)
    - N-Q (Box 8)
    - R-S (Box 9)
    - T-Z (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1908 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1909-1910 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1909, Feb-Apr (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1910 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1910 (Box 15)
  - Personal receipts, 1910-1911 (Box 16)
  - Personal receipts, 1911-1912 (Box 17)
  - Van Veachten Rogers, 1911-1922 (Box 18)
  - Central N. Y. Music Festival
    - [General], 1912-1913 (Box 19, 20)
    - A-L, 1912-1920 (Box 21)
    - M-Z, 1912-1920 (Box 22)
    - [General], 1913-1914 (Box 23)
    - [General], 1913-1915 (Box 24)
    - [General], 1914 (Box 25)
    - [General], 1916 (Box 32)
  - Gertrude Ina Robinson, 1913-1918 (Box 26)
  - [unknown], 1914-1915 (Box 27)
  - Margaret Wilson, 1914-1922 (Box 28)
  - Woodrow Wilson, 1914-1922 (Box 29)
  - Personal letters, 1915 (Box 30)
  - Personal letters, 1915-1916 (Box 31)
  - Christmas cards, 1916; 1923,; 1925 (Box 33)
  - Christmas cards, 1918; 1922 (Box 34)
  - Personal letters, 1920 (Box 36)
  - Memorial Hall, 1920-1948 (Box 37)
  - Kiwanis Club Records, 1921 (Box 38)
  - Treasurer Nat'l. Asso. of Harpist, 1921-1923 (Box 39)
  - Syra. Symphony Orchestra, 1917-1925 (Box 35)
  - Syra. Symphony Orch. Season, 1921-1922 (Box 40)
  - Syra. Symphony Orch. Season, 1922-1923 (Box 41)
  - Syra. Symphony Orch. Season, 1922-1923 (Box 42)
  - Syra. Symphony Orch. 1924-1925Season (Box 44)
  - Syra. Symphony Orch. Season 1924-1925 Artist (Box 45)
  - Syra. Symphony Orch. Season 1924-1925 A-Z (Box 46)
  - Poultney Bigelow, 1922-1940 (Box 43)
  - Letters, 1924-1928
    - A-C (Box 47)
    - D (Box 48)
    - E-H (Box 49)
    - I-M (Box 50)
    - N-R (Box 51)
    - S-W (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 53)
  - Christmas cards, 1926-1927 (Box 54)
  - Christmas cards, 1928-1930 (Box 55)
  - Letters, 1929-1931
    - A-B (Box 56)
    - C (Box 57)
    - D-E (Box 58)
    - F-Ha (Box 59)
    - H-K (Box 60)
    - M-O (Box 61)
    - O-P (Box 62)
    - S (Box 63)
    - T-Z (Box 64)
  - Letters, 1935-1936
    - Ba-M (Box 65)
    - N-Z (Box 66)
  - Letters, 1936-1938
    - A-G (Box 67)
    - H-P (Box 68)
    - Q-Z (Box 69)
  - Letters Rotary Club, 1942-1943 (Box 70)
  - Letters, 1944-1951
    - A-L (Box 71)
    - M-Z (Box 72)
  - Letters, 1945-1950 (Box 73)
- Daily calendars
  - Calendars, March-December, 1905; January, 1906;; March, 1906 (Box 74)
  - Calendars, April-December, 1906 (Box 75)
  - Calendars, August-December, 1907 (Box 76)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1908 (Box 77)
  - Calendars, January-August, 1909 (Box 78)
  - Calendars, September-December, 1909 (Box 79)
  - Calendars, January-July, 1910 (Box 80)
  - Calendars, August-December, 1910 (Box 81)
  - Calendars, January-June, 1911 (Box 82)
  - Calendars, July-December, 1911 (Box 83)
  - Calendars, January-June, 1912 (Box 84)
  - Calendars, July-December, 1912 (Box 85)
  - Calendars, January-June, 1913 (Box 86)
  - Calendars, July-December, 1913 (Box 87)
  - Calendars, January-June, 1914 (Box 88)
  - Calendars, July-December, 1914 (Box 89)
  - Calendars, January-June, 1915 (Box 90)
  - Calendars, July-December, 1915 (Box 91)
  - Calendars, January-June, 1916 (Box 92)
  - Calendars, July-December, 1916 (Box 93)
  - Calendars, January-June, 1917 (Box 94)
  - Calendars, July-December, 1917 (Box 95)
  - Calendars, January-June, 1918 (Box 96)
  - Calendars, July-December, 1918 (Box 97)
  - Calendars, September-December, 1919 (Box 98)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1920 (Box 99)
  - Calendars, January-June, 1921 (Box 100)
  - Calendars, July-December, 1921 (Box 101)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1922 (Box 102)
  - Calendars, January-April, 1923 (Box 103)
  - Calendars, May-December, 1923 (Box 104)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1924 (Box 105)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1925 (Box 106)
  - January-December, 1926 (Box 107)
  - January-December, 1927 (Box 108)
  - Calendars, January 1928; October 1930,; 1933 (Box 109)
  - Calendars, February-September, 1929 (Box 110)
  - Calendars, May-December, 1931 (Box 111)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1932 (Box 112)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1934 (Box 113)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1935 (Box 114)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1936 (Box 115)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1937 (Box 116)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1938 (Box 117)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1939 (Box 118)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1942 (Box 119)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1947 (Box 120)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1948 (Box 121)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1949 (Box 122)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1950 (Box 123)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1951 (Box 124)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1952 (Box 125)
  - Calendars, January-December, 1953 (Box 126)
- Reference files
  - Aero Station Plans, 4 volumes (Box 127)
  - A (Box 128)
  - B (Box 129)
  - C (Box 130-133)
  - D-E-F (Box 134)
  - F-G-H (Box 135)
  - Harp (Box 136-138)
  - L (Box 139)
  - M (Box 140-142)
  - N. A. M. M. [National Association of Music Merchants], 1930-1944 (Box 143, 144)
  - N-O-P-Q (Box 145)
  - Organs (Box 146)
  - Pianos (Box 147)
  - R (Box 148)
  - S (Box 149)
  - T-U-V (Box 150)
  - W-Z (Box 151)
- Miscellaneous
  - Scrapbook, Advertisers using musical instruments (Oversize 1)
  - "Instructions for Playing the Clark Irish Harp" with music by Van Veachten Rogers, oversize softcover volumes, Lessons I through X; 10 volumes (Oversize 1)
  - Insurance and miscellaneous (Box 152)
  - Miscellaneous (to be filed) (Box 153)
  - Photos (Box 154, 155)